Karen Bao

Product Designer with 8 years of experience | 70% design, 30% research

baoruiling@hotmail.com +1 (778) 681-3152 karenbao.github.io linkedin.com/in/ruilingbao

Experience

Sr. Product Designer @ RBCx

Vancouver, Canada

Dec 2022 - Present, Sr. Product Designer, Mydoh

Mentored and supported 2 product designers to uphold the quality bar, while leading high-visibility projects to upgrade key aspects of the product experience.

Child Home Refresh: Revamped the Mydoh child app's Home tab, resulting in a ~9% increase in key feature engagement rate.

Earn Redesign: Overhauled chore creation and management, achieving a 100% task success rate in usability testing.

App Usability Benchmark: Initiated and partnered with Research to establish product usability baselines, guiding optimization efforts.

Design Operations: Led design team rituals, like capacity planning, design reviews, etc., to drive internal design collaboration.

Jul 2021 - Dec 2022, Sr. Product Designer, Dr.Bill

Hired as the 1st designer for Dr.Bill platforms. Partnered with Product and Engineering to produce, validate and deliver end-to-end product experience.

Design System: Established the product's design system, ensuring consistency and simplicity.

Sr. Product Designer @ Flybits Inc.

Toronto, Canada

Nov 2019 - Jul 2021

Partnered with cross-functional stakeholders to conduct user research and craft solutions for the mobile channel.

White-label Mobile Content Templates: Streamlined content templates for pilot credit card and consumer banking use cases.

UX / UI Designer @ FreshWorks Studio Inc.

Victoria, Canada

Feb 2018 - Aug 2019

Worked closely with PM, Business Analysts, Developers and QAs to craft digital solutions for cross-industry clients, including Harbour Air, Hootsuite, BC Government, etc.

Intern, UX Designer @ SAP Canada Inc.

Montreal, Canada

Oct 2016 - Apr 2017

Supported designing the Retail Assortment Planning web application, utilizing the SAP Fiori design system to address design challenges.

About

UX/UI designer with 8 years of experience in both consumer and enterprise product design.

I love spending time to analyze and create simple, intuitive product experiences that solve real user problems. I'm currently based in Vancouver, Canada.

Education

The Centre for Digital Media @ Simon Fraser University

Master of Digital Media 2015 - 2017

Shanghai International Studies University

B.A. in Advertising 2011 - 2015

Skills

Design

Workshop Facilitations
Object-Oriented UX
Wireframing
Prototyping
Interaction Design
Usability Testing

Tools

Figma
Principle
Webflow
HTML/CSS
Adobe Creative Suite